<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Whereas a commission under the Great Seal of England, bearing date at Westminster the three and twentieth day of August now last past, hath been directed unto me, and divers others in the said commission nominated, authorizing the said commissioners, or any four or more of them, by such ways and means as therein is directed, to enquire within the city and diocess of Canterbery in the county of Kent, as well within liberties as without, for the due execution of the statute made made in the three and fortieth  year of the raign of our late soveraign Lady Queen Elizabeth ... Given under my hand this fourth day of September, in the year of our Lord 1683.</title>
            <author>Church of England. Province of Canterbury. Archbishop (1678-1690 : Sancroft)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1683</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B09948</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S569A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R186431</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">69648880</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 69648880</idno>
            <idno type="VID">185045</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B09948)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 185045)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2885:4)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Whereas a commission under the Great Seal of England, bearing date at Westminster the three and twentieth day of August now last past, hath been directed unto me, and divers others in the said commission nominated, authorizing the said commissioners, or any four or more of them, by such ways and means as therein is directed, to enquire within the city and diocess of Canterbery in the county of Kent, as well within liberties as without, for the due execution of the statute made made in the three and fortieth  year of the raign of our late soveraign Lady Queen Elizabeth ... Given under my hand this fourth day of September, in the year of our Lord 1683.</title>
                  <author>Church of England. Province of Canterbury. Archbishop (1678-1690 : Sancroft)</author>
                  <author>Sancroft, William, 1617-1693.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1683]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed: "W. Cant."</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Church of England --  Clergy --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Church of England --  Government --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Church of England --  Charities --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-04</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-05</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:185045:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>WHEREAS a Commiſſion under the Great Seal of <hi>England,</hi> bearing date at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> the Three and Twentieth day of <hi>Auguſt</hi> now laſt paſt, hath been directed unto Me, and divers others in the ſaid Commiſſion nominated, Authorizing the ſaid Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, or any Four or more of them, by ſuch Ways and Means as therein is di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected, to enquire within the City and Dioceſs of <hi>Canterbury</hi> in the County of <hi>Kent,</hi> as well within Liberties as without, for the due Execution of the Statute made in the Three and Fortieth year of the Raign of our late Sove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raign Lady Queen <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> what Lands, Tenements, Rents, Annuities, Profits, Hereditaments, Goods, Chattels. Money, and Stocks of Money, have been heretofore given by any well-diſpoſed Perſon or Perſons for Relief of Aged, Impotent, and Poor People, Maintenance of Sick and Maimed Soldiers and Mariners, Schools of Learning, Free-Schools, and Scholars of Univerſities, Repair of Bridges, Ports, Havens, Cauſeways, Churches, Sea-Banks, and High-ways, for Education and Preferment of Orphans, for or to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the Relief, Stock or Maintenance for Houſes of Correction, Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage of Poor Maids, Supportation, Aid and Help of young Tradeſmen, Han<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dycrafts-men, and Perſons decayed, Releaſe and Redemption of Captives, Aid or Eaſe of any Poor Inhabitants, concerning Payment of Fifteens, Set<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting out of Soldiers, and other Taxes, and of the Abuſes, Breaches of Truſt, Negligences, Miſimployment, not Imploying, Concealing, Defrauding, Miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>converting and Miſgoverning of the ſame Lands, Tenements, Stocks of Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, and other Things given to any of the Charitable Uſes aforeſaid, and to ſet down ſuch Orders, Judgments and Decrees, as that the ſame Lands, Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, Money, and other things may be duly imployed to and for ſuch of the Charitable Uſes aforeſaid for which they were given, limited or ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed by the Donors and Founders thereof:</p>
            <p>Theſe are therefore to Will and Require you, the next Lords Day after the receipt of this Order, in your Pariſh-Church after the <hi>Nicene</hi> Creed, publickly to Read the ſame; to the end that all Perſons may know it, and have the benefit thereof. And that all due Proceedings may be had for Recovery and Settlement for the future of ſuch Charitable Uſes as have been miſconverted and miſimployed, I have appointed <hi>Tho. Bourchier</hi> Doctor of Laws, our Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſary of <hi>Canterbury, George Thorpe</hi> Doctor in Divinity, one of the Preben<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>daries of <hi>Canterbury,</hi> and <hi>William Man</hi> Eſquire, or any one of them, to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive all ſuch Complaints as ſhall be made. And that all Perſons concerned may come fully prepared, they are to produce to the Perſons aboveſaid, or ſome one of them, all ſuch Wills, Charters, Evidences, and other Writings, whereby the reſpective Charities were given, limited and appointed, who will then give them ſuch further direction as ſhall be neceſſary for the due Proſecution of ſuch Complaints.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Given under my Hand <date>this fourth day of <hi>September,</hi> in the Year of our Lord 1683.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>W. Cant.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
